Chris Marchetti

Littleton, CO

Phone: 303.941.4211 | Email: cmarche2ti@gmail.com | Web: https://cmarche2ti.github.io/ | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrismarchetti | Github: https://github.com/cmarche2ti

SUMMARY

Data Analyst working primarily in Python, with extensive experience as a mathematics educator. Experienced in SQL, Machine Learning, JavaScript, VBA & HTML. A lifelong learner, who enjoys solving complex problems with a team. Able to distill difficult concepts into clear, concise explanations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript, NoSQL, HTML/CSS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Data Manipulation and Visualization: Pandas, Matplotlib, Tableau, Excel

Other: Git, Flask, Bootstrap, Command line

PROJECTS

Flask Blog

Lead

- Github repository: https://github.com/cmarche2ti/flask-blog
- Project Deployed at: http://cmarche2ti.pythonanywhere.com/
- Personal blog coded from scratch. Allows users to create accounts and posts. Users may also edit and delete posts.
- Tools: Flask, SQLAlchemy, Python, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

MLB Hall of Fame

Lead

- Github repository: https://github.com/cmarche2ti/mlb-hall-of-fame
- Project Deployed at: https://mlb-hof.herokuapp.com/
- Machine Learning project to predict if players should be inducted into the MLB Hall of Fame based on their statistics alone.
- Responsibilities: Machine Learning, Front End and Back End development
- Tools: Flask, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQL, JavaScript, Scikitlearn, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib

MaryJane Website

Team Lead

- Github repository: https://github.com/cmarche2ti/mary-jane-dashboard
- Dashboard website showing relationships between Marijuana businesses & crime in the Denver Metro Area
- Responsibilities: Created Website UI, integrated visualizations
- Tools: Flask, HTML, CSS, Leaflet, JavaScript, Python, Pandas

Chris Marchetti

Does Foreign Aid Effect HDI

Team Lead

- Github repository: https://github.com/cmarche2ti/ForeignAid-HDI-Project
- The US and World Bank give aid to many countries, the project sought to determine if this aid improved a country's Human Development Index.
- Responsibilities: cleaned and merged data and created visualizations, prepared final Jupyter notebook.
- Tools: Python, Pandas, Matplotlib

EXPERIENCE

Sofware Developer

July, 2020-Present

Datateer - Contract

Remote

Troubleshoot ETL pipelines using the Singer framework and Python. Communicate issues and plan of action with client.

Data Visualization Tutor

June, 2020-Present

Trilogy Education

Remote

Support students in Data Visualization programs with Python, Pandas, SQL, Tableau and other technologies.

Senior Instructor Colorado Academy 2013-June, 2020

Denver, CO

Taught Mathematics and Introduction to Computer Science including, Multivariable Calculus, Calculus BC, Pre-Calculus, Geometry and Algebra.

- Lead the development of curriculum and assessments with course level teams.
- Established and led a Summer Math Program for incoming 9th graders.

Mathematics Teacher Littleton High School

2002-2013

Littleton, CO

Taught mathematics including IB Mathematics HL & SL, AP Calculus AB & BC, Pre-Calculus and Algebra.

- Instrumental in bringing computer science classes to the school.
- Boettcher Distinguished Teacher

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certificate: University of Denver, Denver, CO

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Python, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Machine Learning, Tableau, Big Data, HTML/CSS, Excel, and VBA.

Master of Arts in Educational Technology: Regis University, Denver, CO

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics: Montclair State University, Montclair, NJ